the man who had his ears severed
remember that whose seventies year Peter
man of God
severed somebody else's ear in the name
of Jesus you ever had someone sever your
ear in the name of Jesus beloved many of
us are walking around crippled we're
walking around with an ear cut off
because because of what someone else did
to us we're walking around with lame
feet or withered hands we're walking
around with eyes I cannot see or ears I
cannot hear we're alive
but we're incapacitated and when jesus
healed these incapacitated people he was
basically telling us listen as I healed
your eyes physically so I can heal your
spiritual eyesight but of a God is still
working miracles to us and reveal your
miracle working power in Jesus name we
pray amen the title of the message today
is the message of the miracles of Christ
how many of you would give anything to
be back in the day when Jesus walked the
earth and worked miracles right to
actually see that a lot of people asked
a question like how come we don't see
those kinds of miracles today how many
of you would like to see those kinds of
miracles today we know that our
prophetically speaking when the
outpouring of the Holy Spirit happens in
full measure that God's people will work
miracles amen how many of you would like
to be a miracle worker of course all you
want to be
that's a very dangerous thing huh
because you can end up taking glory to
yourself but I want to talk to you today
about the purpose or rather why Jesus
performed miracles and I am going to let
you know that out for those of you which
is a lot of you that were not present
this past Wednesday night Terry shared a
devotional thought about 20 minutes and
as soon as he finished the devotional
thought I let Terry know that his
devotional thought was stolen I told him
I'm taking it and so what I'm gonna be
showing today is actually based off of
what he shared Wednesday night and just
very powerful powerful thought but I
want you two to turn with me in your
Bibles to the book of Mark chapter 9
mark chapter 9 and we'll read verses 1 &
2 mark chapter 9 verses 1 & 2 the Bible
said God says and he said unto them
assuredly I say to you is that the right
verse it is not I think we're in Matthew
chapter 9 I think I may have written
that down incorrectly let me see Matthew
chapter 9
there we go Matthew 9 Matthew 9 not Mark
9 but Matthew chapter 9 beginning with
verse 1 so the Bible says and he entered
into a ship and passed over and came
into his own City verse 2 and behold
they brought to him a man sick of the
palsy lying on his bed or lying on a bed
and Jesus seeing their faith said unto
the sick of the palsy son be of good
cheer thy sins be what be forgiven thee
I'm not sure if you see the the
interesting thing in this verse the the
man that is sick of the palsy appears
not to ask Jesus anything he doesn't say
I'm sick he doesn't speak according to
the text he doesn't say anything the
friends that bring him don't say
anything that is according to the text
and this is very interesting because the
Bible says Jesus seeing their faith how
do you see faith well just just I just
want you to think about this okay Jesus
seen their faith what is faith faith
faith is the substance of things hoped
for the evidence of things not seen
where do where does faith abide in the
heart can can you can you draw faith no
faith is not a physical thing but the
Bible says that Jesus what seeing their
faith what does that mean Jesus had to
have seen what was going on in their
minds so I want you to catch this no
conversation they
bring the man to Jesus and and notice
what now now let me ask you just I just
want you to think if you were Jesus what
if the first thing you would say you see
this man he cannot move what you say to
him
be healed how yet I'll take up your bed
and walk but apparently this is not what
the man really wants because Jesus gives
the man what he really wants he wants
his sins to be forgiven and so Jesus I
mean think about it now if it's near you
we're gonna say hey be of good cheer
take up your bed and walk you're
physically healed now be of good cheer
but Jesus says no no no jesus says be of
good share your what your sins are
forgiven you I want you to catch this
had Jesus stopped right there would this
man have gone away happy I'm asking you
what do you think otherwise Jesus would
not have said hey you know what
be of good cheer your prayer has been
answered this man valued forgiveness of
sins over the ability to walk now let me
ask you a question when Jesus said your
sins be forgiven you did a miracle take
place
yeah did the people see the miracle no
in fact look at the next verse verse 3
and behold certain of the scribes said
we're okay so just pause for a second
okay and I want you to imagine this
scene in your mind no words are being
spoken the friends bring the man to
Jesus no word is said Jesus reads their
what their minds their thoughts and does
not say to them take up your bed and
walk he says to him your sins are
forgiven you and a miracle has just
occurred now I want to share something
with you are the men that are around are
they amazed
is anyone amazed when Jesus says your
sins are forgiven you know in the human
world
no one's amazed in fact the Pharisees
think that Jesus has just one blaspheme
so they don't see any miracle nobody's
amazed now let's change scenes the
angels are they mazed are they like whoa
how does he do that how does he make sin
disappear that is just mind-blowing
are the Angels like what did we just see
yeah in angel world a miracle has just
occurred but in human world we don't see
anything
so now remember no words have been
spoken Jesus simply says your sins are
forgiven you be of good cheer
now the scribes and Pharisees say where
within themselves this manhwa blasphemes
now look at the next verse verse 4 verse
4 and let me share something with you
can you go back to verse 2 just go back
to verse 2 very quickly
so when the Bible says and behold they
brought - they brought to him a man sick
of the palsy lying on on a bed and Jesus
seeing their faith seen the Greek word
there actually means to know so jesus
knew their faith but the word see is
used in the English what it means is
Jesus knew what they were thinking in
their minds now go back to verse 4
because the same word the same Greek
word is used where it says in Jesus
knowing their thoughts meaning Jesus
what seeing their thoughts said
wherefore thinkI evil where in your
hearts next verse
for whether is easier to say or which is
easier to say thy sin be what
forgivingly or to say arise and walk not
am answer question in aims a world which
is easier which is easier take up your
dead end
walk that's not a miracle in angel world
are you catching what I'm saying like
Jesus walking on water is not a miracle
in angel world we do this stuff all the
time in angel world but the forgiveness
of sins making sin disappear that is a
miracle in angel world but Jesus knows
that man can't see as angels see so
Jesus says okay alright alright I have
to bring this down to your level so
which is easier what do you think - say
your sins are forgiven you or take up
your bed and walk and in human world
what's easier your sins are forgiven you
because we can't see that and we dot
that the sins are really forgiven so
Jesus what's this he says which is
easier take up your bed and walk or your
sins be and in their minds what are they
thinking it's harder to say take up your
bed and walk
Jesus says no notice the next verse
verse six Jesus says but that you may
know that the Son of man has walked
power on earth to forgive sins what kind
of power is that forgive sins then he's
saved to the sick of the palsy Watts
arise take up your bed and go into your
house naps our Angels in angel world
going oh because that's cool stuff to
them they were already like oh when
Jesus said what your sins are forgiven
you but now in human world they're not
impressed when Jesus says your sins are
forgiven you but when Jesus says take up
your bed and walk and they see this man
get up what are they thinking their
minds are blown where is the true
miracle in the forgiveness of sins that
sets the foundation for what we're going
to talk about today because Jesus used
the physical miracle to teach a
spiritual lesson with me Jesus did not
come to earth to perform miracles to
show off or to say hey look at what I
can do every miracle he performed was
designed to teach a spiritual lesson are
you with me so the Bible tells us that
Jesus performed somewhere around 40 or
so miracles that's a lot of miracles and
guess what we'll go through all those
miracles today don't pass on we're not
going through each one we're just gonna
juice these miracles down so are you
ready there are five sets of miracles
that Jesus performed and we're going to
categorize these five sets of miracles
and then talk about what each one of
them means for us to
so the first set of miracles we will
call the life miracles you can call it
the death miracles or the life miracles
and those that are the miracles where
Jesus brought someone from the from the
dead so who do we have in these miracles
Lazarus the widow's son and Jerry's his
daughter right those are the three
people that Jesus resurrected from the
dead now turn with me quickly if you
will or see if we can get up on the
screen mark chapter 5 verse 23 and 24
the Bible says and besought him greatly
that is the the Darius's daughter
besought him greatly saying my little
daughter lieth at the point of death i
pray thee come and lay thy hands on her
that she may be healed and she shall
live verse 24 and Jesus went with them
and once people followed him and
thronged him so so the girl is about to
die and we know that she eventually dies
what is the father doing on her behalf
he's asking Jesus to heal her you'll
find the same thing with in John chapter
11 verse 33 John chapter 11 verse 33
when Jesus therefore saw her weeping
that is Mary and the Jews also weeping
with weeping which came with her he
groaned in spirit and was troubled why
is Jesus groaning in spirit not only did
they not have faith but did he feel
their empathy yeah and then what about
this man that the widow's son that dies
did Jesus have compassion on the widow's
son and is that why she was raised yeah
in all three instances listen carefully
in all three instances the people that
were dead could not appeal to God for
themselves did you catch what I just
said the people that were dead could not
appeal to God for themselves why very
good the living know that they shall die
but the dead won't know nothing so what
was the purpose of these death miracles
or life miracles they were to show
that Jesus could raise people from the
dead you're not catching me Jesus has
power to raise people from the dead who
are the dead let me ask you do we have
anyone in here today who was once dead
you beloved are a miracle you are here
right now because of the miracle-working
power of Jesus he raised you from the
dead what do I mean I need to get more
specific now because you see the dead
can't speak for themselves
somebody was praying for you because you
could care less about God come on how
many dead people how many people do we
have in here that were one-time dead you
didn't you couldn't even appeal to God
for yourself because you could care less
so somebody else was praying for you
your mother your father a neighbor
somebody was praying for you and because
of their prayers God interceded and rose
you from the dead beloved if you if you
are a miracle in here today I'm just
gonna ask you to stand right where you
are I just want to see a miracle there's
a miracle there's a miracle
there's a miracle there's a wow wow you
mean God is still doing miracles Wow
look all these miracles here thing that
is exciting that's exciting stuff but
now that God has power to raise from the
dead Ephesians 2:1 and you has he
quickened who were dead in trespasses
and sins where in time past ye walked
according to the course of this world
according to the Prince of the power of
the air the spirit that now worketh in
the children of disobedience and whom
and whom also we all had our
conversations in time past in the lusts
of the flesh fulfilling the desires of
the flesh and of the mind and we're by
nature the children of Wrath even as of
but God who is rich in His mercy for for
his great love wherewith he loved us
even when we were dead in sin
has he quickened us together with Christ
and has raised us up and made us sit in
heavenly places beloved while you may
look at the actual resurrection of the
dead as a great miracle at the end of
time the greater miracle is when a soul
is resurrected spiritually some of you
are still dead yeah you're still here
you're here you might be in church but
you're still did guess what the same pod
who raised up Lazarus from the dead the
same God who you just looked around and
saw other people who were once dead and
now alive that same God can work a
miracle in your life and raise you from
the dead God is still working miracles
the second set of miracles are what we
will call the physical miracles these
are the miracles such as the blind being
able to see and the death being able to
hear and the paralytic and the man with
the withered hand and the man with the
the men with leprosy and the woman with
the issue of blood and Peters
mother-in-law with the fever all of
these were physical healings are you
with me so these people were not dead
they were alive but incapacitated they
were alive but crippled their minds were
operating but they were but they were
not operating physically on the level
that they should have Peter's mother had
a fever means her body was inflamed the
word literally means to be on fire and
when you have a fever
it means your body has an infection are
you with me there were those who were
blind there were those who were
paralyzed and not walking and I want you
to understand because when jesus healed
these people he was
teaching a symbolic lesson because you
see some of you were blind to the truth
but Jesus did a miracle and open your
eyes do we have any miracle why some of
you are deaf and could not hear the Word
of God but guess what God did a miracle
and open your ears
some of you were paralyzed you could not
go what God wanted you to go but God
healed you so that you could walk to
fulfill his mission
some of you were could not use your hand
to do what God called you to do you had
a withered hand and God did something
amazing He healed your hand so that you
could work on God's behalf do we have
any miracles in here today beloved God
is still working miracles and the
miracle of healing you spiritually is
greater than the miracle of healing you
physically leprosy was a symbol of sin
and uncleanness and those who had
leprosy had to be separated from
everyone else just like the woman with
the issue of blood it was an issue of
uncleanness and she lived her life in
isolation there was the man who had his
ears severed remember that who severed
his ear Peter man of God
severed somebody else's ear in the name
of Jesus you ever had someone sever your
ear in the name of Jesus you ever have
someone do something bad to you in the
name of Jesus beloved many of us are
walking around crippled we're walking
around with an ear cut off because
because of what someone else did to us
we're walking around with lame feet or
withered hands we're walking around with
eyes I cannot see or ears I cannot hear
we're alive we're alive but we're
incapacitated and when jesus healed
these incapacitated people he was
basically telling us listen as I healed
your eyes physically so I can heal your
spiritual eyesight
beloved God is still working miracles
some of you were brought up in the
church you're alive but you're lame
don't think that as an insult you're
late you can't walk you can't do the
things God wants you to do because you
are a crippled Christian you've heard
the truth over and over again and it's
now it's just like it goes in one ear
and out the other
you don't see what other people get
excited about you can't feel leprosy you
couldn't you can't feel the moving of
the Holy Spirit and God says listen if
you let me I will heal you God is still
in the business of healing beloved and
and and if we allow him to he will work
that miracle where angels will go Wow
you see listen to me walking on water
doesn't impress angels but when someone
curses you out and you don't respond
back in the way that you used to they
are like wow when you don't let your
children get under your skin parents
husband and why when you don't get into
that art that's that's when angels are
like whoa did you just see that I just
saw a miracle do you think God is still
trying to work miracles today
absolutely beloved absolutely so number
one what kind of miracles the death
miracles number two what else the
physical miracles and now now the nature
miracles
help me were the nature miracles Jesus
walking on water
Jesus calming the storms the fig tree
that with it these were the nature
miracles what was Jesus seeking to
demonstrate in these nature miracles
that he had power over the elements of
nature Jesus trying to show us listen I
have power over nature now you do
realize that there are two types of
nature and Jesus has power over both
nature's he has power over nature and he
also has power over nature so God's
trying to show us listen I know I know
how the human heart can be a storm I
know how you can get dragged down
underneath the waves of the attitudes of
people's nations multitudes and tongues
I know what it's like to be sucked down
by gravity excuse me
refrain I know what you are going
through when you are sucked down by
gravity because Jesus was never sucked
up by gravity amen
so Jesus is telling us in this miracle
working power he's saying listen I know
what it's like I understand I've been
through the temptations as you are but
I'm telling you I can calm the storm in
your hearts you ever deal with storms in
your art come on you you know what you
you sometimes you have storms towards
other people that you just can't seem to
control man every time I look at you I
just discussed
I can't help I loved hating you beloved
and look we know in our hearts when we
do something wrong right
but sometimes the human element the
human nature is so strong we feel like
we're in the midst of that storm and we
can't control it but Jesus says listen
if you let me into your life I'm trying
when I calm the storm I'm trying to show
you that's not impressive that's nothing
to me angels in heaven are not like whoa
jesus said peace be still and the storm
still they're not impressed that's
that's mundane stuff in the unseen world
but when Jesus says to your heart peace
be still that beloved is a miracle two
angels sees humans we get caught up in
the whoa he was able to steal the storms
and Jesus like don't you see what I'm
trying to show you don't you see what
I'm trying to tell you I'm trying to
demonstrate to you that if I can if I
can show you power over the things you
can see what about the things that you
can't see how many of you know what it's
like to have victory over a storm you're
a miracle God worked a miracle in you I
know I'm a miracle growing up I had I
had an anger problem
yeah me you know I tell you all the time
at the drop of a hat I'd be in a fight
boom like that mountain bag my my good
friends they would hate going out with
me because they knew that at the party
somehow or another I was going to be the
one ending up in a fight
and God has changed me
praise God I don't know what storms you
have faced but guess what I believe that
God has changed many of you if you can
look back and say when I was in the
world I had this problem or that problem
if this is not just something that that
one person alone experiences but we all
have our own storms but I love it when
you can look back and say I used to you
know what that is that is evidence of
God's miracle-working power in you all
right we got two more sets of miracles
but let's recap number one the life
miracles number two the physical
miracles number three the nature
miracles by the way some of you are
still struggling you still have no
control over your storms the same God
who was able to calm the storm 2000
years ago is the same God that can calm
the storm in your heart right now it's
the same God who can keep you above the
gravity of sin that's why the Bible says
now unto him that is able to keep you
from falling the same God that kept
Peter from falling under the waves is
the same God that can keep you from
falling under the ways of your own human
nature the fourth set of miracles the
sustenance miracles the sustenance
miracles talk to me what of those
right when he fed the the 5000 and the
4000 with the loaves of bread and the
and the fishes what else when he turns
water into wine
what else how about when he catches the
fish yeah those are the those are the
sustenance miracles we understand that
that when Jesus was performing this
miracle turning the water into wine he
was actually pointing to himself did you
realize that what is wine symbolic of in
the scripture blood he's blood remember
at the last how he gives them wine and
says this is my word blood which is shed
you he was pointing to himself as the
one that would sustain them breaking the
bread same thing the feet that the
giving of the bread same thing I am the
bread of life and what Jesus is trying
to tell us listen I have power to
sustain you in your walk with I want
sustain you through my body
I will sustain you through my blood I
will sustain you through my word and
beloved listen don't worry if the bread
is gonna run out I tell you something
okay I think I've managed to share this
with you before my very first sermon
that I ever preached that showed us with
you before yes some of you remember my
very first sermon that I ever preached
was two hours long I had been Adventist
for about maybe five months six months
somewhere around there and when they
asked me to preach what I ended up doing
is I ended up putting everything I knew
about Adventism into that one sermon and
the sermon took me about maybe like
three weeks to prepare so after I
preached that sermon and by the way
people were like oh wow I've never heard
anything like this before this was that
was amazing and I remember thinking to
myself if it took me three weeks to
prepare this sermon and that time I
wanted to be a pastor I was just like
how in the world
will I prepare a sermon every week for
the rest of my life I was terrified
because I was like how am I gonna do
this
I mean in my mind the bread was gonna
run out but loved it the bread does not
run out the bread does not run out I
mean does not run out God will always
sustain you and beloved listen to me
here is the miracle you see some of us
were starving starving for truth and God
says listen I am going to come into your
lives and I will feed you
I will provide enough sustenance for you
to keep you from being malnourished
beloved that's a miracle you remain in
the church because Jesus sustains you
that is a miracle
all right so miracle not a miracle set
number one the life miracles number two
the physical miracles number three the
names of miracles number four the
sustenance miracles and now number five
number five is what I call the warfare
miracles what are those what are the
water miracles what what are the
miracles that we have not covered thus
far it's the only it's probably the most
exciting miracles of Jesus the scariest
miracles of Jesus the miracles of
casting out demons the spiritual warfare
miracles where demons are coming up to
here my name is legion we are many and
we have this guy on lockdown and Jesus
says no you don't get out so brother
Terry was sharing on Wednesday night and
this is what led me to this sermon
because he was you know one guy had a
demon this demon was was was blind
yes and I'm sorry not blind he was mute
and deaf he could not hear and he could
not speak see sometimes we don't hear
the word of God because of our own
issues you know man I got so much stuff
going but sometimes it's demonic because
sometimes you can be sitting in church
and not hearing and that's a demon of
dumbness of deafness working to keep the
Word of God from penetrating your hearts
so when demons were cast people into the
fire that's what the devil will do he
will make you do stupid stuff to
yourself throw yourself in bad
situations he will leave you to be blind
he will lead you to be dumb he leaves
you to cut yourself in other words to
harm yourself and Jesus says listen I
when I cast out these demons I'm not
just trying to show you humanity that I
have power over demons I'm trying to
show you that I can cast out the demonic
influences in your life yes God is still
working miracles
don't let the demon of dumbness or the
demon of deafness or the demon of
muteness where you can't even open your
mouth to say God come into my heart you
remember one guy just came before Jesus
he couldn't even speak because the
demons were in him and Jesus was able to
read his hearts but I would listen to me
God is about miracles and he's still
doing miracles today and that miracle is
the miracle of a changed life that is
the greatest move now look at you look
at you
you just did exactly what I was hoping
you wouldn't when I said that is a
miracle of a change life you guys are
lying mmm-hmm yeah but we want to see
somebody walk on water though beloved
the angels are like what his life has
changed her life has changed man we need
to this is absolutely amazing that's
what the true miracle is first
Corinthians chapter 1 verse 24 we're
getting ready to close 1st Corinthians
chapter 1 verse 24 I've got two more
statements I need to read to you the
Bible says but unto them which are
called both Jews and Greeks Christ the
law you know that word power means in
the Greek it means miracle Christ the
miracle of God listen what does that
mean the miracle working power of God is
Christ so what's this if Christ is in
you did you hear what I just said if
Christ is in you listen listen I wrote
this down so I could say it right okay
are you ready if Christ is in you listen
carefully he will raise you from the
dead he will heal your inactivity cause
you to walk in his spirit and put forth
your hand in his name and he will heal
your leprosy of sin and restore your
hearing and open your eyes he will give
you power over the storms of the human
hearts and the waters of human nature
and cause you to walk above the gravity
of sin he will sustain you with an
endless supply of his body the bread of
life and his blood which was shed for
you and use you to feed and sustain
others and He will give you power over
serpents and spiritual wickedness in
high places so that no weapon formed
against you shall prosper in other words
you will be my greatest miracle
I need you to listen to these two
statements they are powerful the first
one is from testimonies to ministers
page 49 and it says this angels are
amazed as they behold the transformation
of character
stop have you ever been amazed at
something like truly amazed what are
some things you'd be amazed at somebody
walking on water yeah
somebody levitating yeah that's what
that's what would amaze us right angels
are amazed as they behold the
transformation of character brought
about in those who yield themselves to
God that's what amazes angels here's one
more the Lord Jesus is making
experiments on human hearts through the
exhibition of his mercy and abundant
grace he's affecting transformations so
amazing that Satan with all his
triumphant boasting with all his
Confederacy of evil united against God
and the laws of his government stands
viewing them as a fortress impregnable
to his Sophos trees and delusions they
are to him and in comprehensible mystery
how many of you would like to be an
incomprehensible mystery to Satan
wait what hold on I just got this guy to
go curse him out to go curse her out and
she didn't respond the way we know she
should what is going on that is the kind
of thing that blows Satan's mind when
you're driving down the highway and
someone gives you sign language and you
don't sign back that is miracle-working
power to angels beloved when you learn
how to hold your tongue
you know the Bible says that the tongue
is a world of fire and it sets
everything on fire beloved listen to me
when you exchange your tongue of fire
for tongues of fire under my tongues on
fire with the love of God when you
exchange our beloved that's what appears
that's what is a miracle to angels and
so my appeal to you today is Lord make
me a miracle make me a miracle I am
tired of succumbing to human nature I'm
tired of walking around crippled I am
tired of not being able to do what
you've asked me to do because my legs
won't take me the places that you asked
me to go my hands won't do the things
you ask me to do because I'm walking
around crippled I am blind I am deaf I
can't feel your spirit Lord I need you
to heal me or it might be that you're
praying for someone who is dead you're
praying for someone who has no care for
God who could care less about God and
you're saying Lord raised him from the
dead I need a miracle if that's you if
you need a miracle on someone else's
behalf or you need a miracle on your own
behalf I'm gonna invite you to stand
where you are nor make me a miracle or
Lord I'm praying for the dead I'm
praying for someone who is spiritually
dead and I need you Lord to resurrect
them but of a God can still do miracles
today and he is still doing miracles
today Heavenly Father we have evidence
before us of your miracle working power
there are people in this place today who
were once dead and are now alive there
are people in this place today who were
once crippled who were once blind who
were once
who once could not could not feel
because leprosy covered them who who
once were trapped by human nature and
Lord you have done something in their
lives to cause them to walk again to
cause them to feel again to cause them
to see to hear Lord we are praying today
now that there are some of us who still
need a miracle in our lives
please Lord remind us of the reason you
performed those miracles and may we by
faith accept your miracle working in our
lives today